<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Apache SIS™ library on Apache SIS</title>
    <link>https://sis.apache.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Apache SIS™ library on Apache SIS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://sis.apache.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apache SIS downloads</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/downloads.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/downloads.html</guid>
      <description>Apache SIS 1.1 is now available. See the release notes for a list of changes since the previous version.
Apache SIS releases are available under the Apache License, Version 2.0. See the NOTICE file contained in each release artifact for applicable copyright attribution notices.
 Download ZIP files   Verify signatures    Download as a Maven dependency   Include non-free resources      Download ZIP files  Apache SIS is distributed in the form of Java source code in a multi-modules Apache Maven project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache SIS team</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/team-list.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/team-list.html</guid>
      <description>Project Management Committee (PMC)  The Project Management Committee (PMC) is the group of people with formal oversight of the project.
 Adam Estrada Alexis Manin Andrew Hart Charitha Madusanka Gregory D. Reddin Johann Sorel Joseph F. White Marc Le Bihan Martin Desruisseaux Nga Thien Chung Olivier Nouguier Patrick O&amp;rsquo;Leary Paul Michael Ramirez Peter Karich Ross Laidlaw Sean William McCleese Suresh Marru Travis Pinney  Committers  Committers are peoples with write access to the source code repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build from source</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/build.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/build.html</guid>
      <description>Apache SIS is built by Maven. For installing the JAR files in the local Maven repository, execute the following command from the SIS project root:
mvn install The JavaFX application is excluded by default because it depends on the JavaFX platform which is distributed under GPL license (note that the SIS module stay under Apache 2 licence). Likewise the EPSG geodetic dataset is excluded by default for licensing reasons. For including the JavaFX module and the use of EPSG dataset in the build:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checkout source code</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/source.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/source.html</guid>
      <description>Apache SIS source code is maintained using Git version control, completed by optional data maintained using Subversion version control. Optional data include in particular the EPSG geodetic dataset, which is subject to licensing terms different than Apache ones. This page describes two ways to checkout Apache SIS source code:
 A basic checkout with only the main repository, the most stable branch, and no configuration requirement. A more advanced configuration for active SIS developments, using uncommitted (for now) API and including optional data for more extensive tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command-line interface</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/command-line.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/command-line.html</guid>
      <description>A command-line interface is provided for extracting information from data files or authority codes, and for performing coordinate operations. That command-line tool is provided for allowing users to experiment some Apache SIS functionalities without writing Java code. For each example, key Java APIs are listed for allowing users to reproduce the functionality in their own application.
 Installation   Optional dependencies    Usage  Examples   Print Coordinate Reference Systems (CRS) definition  Getting a verified EPSG identifier from a Coordinate Reference System  Performing coordinate conversions or transformations  Extracting ISO 19115 Metadata    Performance consideration    Installation  Select &amp;ldquo;Apache SIS 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently asked questions</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/faq.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/faq.html</guid>
      <description>This page lists some Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ) when using Apache SIS.
 Referencing   Getting started   How do I transform a coordinate?  Which map projections are supported?  What is the axis order issue and how is it addressed?    Coordinate Reference Systems   How do I instantiate a Universal Transverse Mercator (UTM) projection?  How do I instantiate a Google projection?  How can I identify the projection kind of a CRS?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use EPSG geodetic dataset</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/epsg.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/epsg.html</guid>
      <description>The EPSG geodetic dataset is a de-facto standard providing thousands of Coordinate Reference System (CRS) definitions together with information about how to perform coordinate operations, their accuracies and their domains of validity. The EPSG dataset is owned and maintained by the International Association of Oil &amp;amp; Gas producers. Usage of EPSG dataset with Apache SIS is optional but strongly recommended: without that geodetic dataset, only a small subset of CRS definitions will be available (basically the constants enumerated in the CommonCRS Java class) unless full definitions are provided in Well Known Text (WKT) or Geographic Markup Language (GML) formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaFX application</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/javafx.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/javafx.html</guid>
      <description>Apache SIS provides an optional JavaFX application for testing SIS capability to read, transform and visualize data files. (note: a command line interface is also available). The graphical application is in early development stage and very far from providing all services that we can expect from a Geographic Information System (GIS). Furthermore this application covers a very small subset of Apache SIS capabilities. But it can give an idea of what is available there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mailing lists</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/mail-lists.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/mail-lists.html</guid>
      <description>We welcome you to join mailing lists and let us know about your thoughts or ideas about Apache SIS. Everyone can subscribe, but note that all emails sent to those lists are archived and publicly readable on the web. See Public Forum Archive Policy for more information.
 Cross-project mailing lists  Geospatial mailing list    Apache SIS mailing lists  User mailing list  Developer mailing list  Issues mailing list  Commit mailing list      Cross-project mailing lists Geospatial mailing list  This is where peoples can ask questions or discuss about geospatial topics that are not specific to Apache SIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New contributor</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/contributor.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/contributor.html</guid>
      <description>Improving and extending Apache SIS requires extensive knowledge of geographic information science, object oriented programming, the Java language, and of the library itself. Contributors should expect that they will need to learn a great deal before being able to become productive. However, the effort required to become productive should improve the contributor&amp;rsquo;s understanding and knowledge of geographic information systems, of geodetic and geographic science, and of effective computer programming.
This document is expected to evolve as the Apache SIS project develops its own mode of operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions fréquentes (FAQ)</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/fr/faq.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/fr/faq.html</guid>
      <description>Cette page liste quelques questions fréquemment posées à propos de Apache SIS. Son contenu est traduit de la page de FAQ en anglais.
 Géoréférencement   Pour bien commencer   Comment transformer une coordonnée ?  Quelles projections sont supportées ?  Qu’est ce que le problème d’ordre des axes et comment est il abordé ?    Systèmes de Référence des Coordonnées   Comment créer une projection de type Transverse Universelle de Mercator (UTM) ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended code patterns</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/code-patterns.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/code-patterns.html</guid>
      <description>This page lists some recommended code pattern for developing or using Apache SIS.
 Referencing   Never explicitely swap coordinates for axis order    Coverages   Georeference images with affine transforms, not bounding boxes    International   Specify timezone  Replace underscores by spaces before sorting  Loop over character sequences using code points    Logging    Referencing  Recommended code pattern when using the sis-referencing module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release management</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-management.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-management.html</guid>
      <description>This page describes how to create and deploy the SIS Maven artifacts, binary bundle, javadoc and list of API changes. The Release FAQ page describes the foundation wide policies. Instructions on this page describe the steps specific to SIS (we do not use the mvn release command). The intended audiences are SIS release managers.
 Configure   Directory layout    Review project status before branching   Update the list of supported CRS  Prepare release notes    Create release branch   Test branch extensively  Prepare non-free resources  Integration test    Deploy Maven artifacts   Verify and close the Nexus release artifacts  Test the Nexus release artifacts    Stage the source, binary and javadoc artifacts   Initialize the distribution directory  Sign and commit  Update online Javadoc  Test the release    Prepare OpenOffice add-in  Prepare Web site  Put the release candidate up for a vote   Recovering from a vetoed release    Finalize the release   Verify release signatures  Announce the release    Update master for the next development cycle   Delete old artifacts on Maven snapshot repository      Configure  Before to perform a release, make sure that the following conditions hold:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release management setup</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-management-setup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-management-setup.html</guid>
      <description>The following instructions need to be done only once by new release managers, or when configuring a new machine for performing the releases. If those steps have already been done, jump directly to the Release Management page.
 Directory layout  Generate GPG key   Web of trust    Maven Configuration &amp;amp; Nexus Setup    Directory layout  The steps described in the release management page assume the following directory layout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source code</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/coding-conventions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/coding-conventions.html</guid>
      <description>This page describes some coding conventions applied in Apache SIS development.
 License header  Naming convention   Internal packages  Substitution for non-existent classes    Code formatting   Import statements  Spaces and line length  Brackets  Member declarations  Exceptions to coding conventions    Documentation formatting   Javadoc annotations  HTML elements   Paragraphs  Javadoc CSS    MathML elements      License header  All Java source files (*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standards implemented by Apache SIS</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/standards.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/standards.html</guid>
      <description>Apache SIS implements the following standards from the Open Geospatial Consortium (OGC), the International Organization for Standardization (ISO) or the Java Community Process (JCP). The same standard is sometime published jointly by both OGC and ISO organizations. Links to free versions of the standards are given when available. The Upgrade needed column indicates that a more recent version of the standard is available but that Apache SIS has not yet been upgraded to that version.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
