<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How to… on Apache SIS</title>
    <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in How to… on Apache SIS</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://sis.apache.org/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Add vertical and temporal axes to an horizontal CRS</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/compound_crs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/compound_crs.html</guid>
      <description>This example creates a 4-dimensional Coordinate Reference System (CRS) with an horizontal, a vertical and a temporal component. While it is possible to create a CompoundCRS programmatically, it is much easier to do that from authority codes when those codes exist. There is two syntaxes standardized by the Open Geospatial Consortium (OGC): One syntax using an identifier starting with http://www.opengis.net/def/crs-compound followed by the components in the query part of the URL, and a shorter but less common syntax starting with urn:ogc:def:crs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compute geodetic distances and paths</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/geodetic_paths.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/geodetic_paths.html</guid>
      <description>The following example computes the geodetic distance between given positions. The geodetic distance is the shortest distance on Earth ellipsoid. Apache SIS can also compute the path as a Béziers curve, with the property that the azimuths at the two curve extremities are preserved.&#xA;Direct dependencies Maven coordinates Module info Remarks org.apache.sis.storage:sis-referencing org.apache.sis.referencing Code example Note that all geographic coordinates below express latitude before longitude.&#xA;import java.awt.Shape; import org.apache.sis.referencing.CommonCRS; import org.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Determine if two CRS are functionally equal</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/crs_equality.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/crs_equality.html</guid>
      <description>Two Coordinate Reference Systems may not be considered equal if they are associated to different metadata (name, identifiers, scope, domain of validity, remarks), even though they represent the same logical CRS. In order to test if two CRS are functionally equivalent, Utilities​.equals­Ignore­Metadata(myFirstCRS, mySecondCRS) can be used.&#xA;In some cases, equals­Ignore­Metadata(…) may fail to see that two reference systems are equal. It may happen for example when two map projections are defined with different parameters, but are mathematically equivalent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From data lake to data cube</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/datalake_to_datacube.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/datalake_to_datacube.html</guid>
      <description>This example opens a few files where each file represent a slice in a data cube. Then the slices are aggregated together in a single multi-dimensional data cube. For example each file may be a raster representing Sea Surface Temperature (SST) at a specific day, and those files can be a aggregated in a single three-dimensional raster with a temporal dimension.&#xA;A current limitation is that each slice must have the same number of dimensions than the data cube.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geographic bounding box of a data file</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/export_metadata_to_xml.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/export_metadata_to_xml.html</guid>
      <description>This example prints the metadata of a netCDF file in the XML format defined by the ISO 19115-3 international standard. The coverage values are not read, only the netCDF file header is read.&#xA;Direct dependencies Maven coordinates Module info Remarks org.apache.sis.storage:sis-netcdf org.apache.sis.storage.netcdf edu.ucar:cdm-core For netCDF-4 or HDF5 The cdm-core dependency can be omitted for netCDF-3 (a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo;), GeoTIFF or any other formats supported by Apache SIS. For the dependencies required for reading GeoTIFF instead of netCDF files, see the geographic bounding box code example.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geographic bounding box of a data file</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/geographic_bounding_box.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/geographic_bounding_box.html</guid>
      <description>This example prints the bounding box of a GeoTIFF image. The pixel values are not read, only the GeoTIFF file header is read. If the file contains many images, the bounding box of each image is printed.&#xA;Direct dependencies Maven coordinates Module info Remarks org.apache.sis.storage:sis-geotiff org.apache.sis.storage.geotiff org.apache.sis.non-free:sis-embedded-data org.apache.sis.referencing.database Optional. Non-Apache license. The EPSG dependency may or may not be needed, depending how the Coordinate Reference System (CRS) is encoded in the GeoTIFF file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get raster values at geographic coordinates</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/raster_values_at_geographic_coordinates.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/raster_values_at_geographic_coordinates.html</guid>
      <description>This example fetches values at given geospatial coordinates in a raster. The coordinates can be expressed in different Coordinate Reference System (CRS). Conversions from geographic or projected coordinates to pixel coordinates, optionally followed by conversions from raster data to units of measurement, are done automatically. Raster data and spatiotemporal coordinates can have more than two dimensions.&#xA;This example assumes a preloaded three-dimensional raster. For the loading part, see read from a netCDF file or read from a GeoTIFF file code examples.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get raster values at pixel coordinates</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/raster_values_at_pixel_coordinates.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/raster_values_at_pixel_coordinates.html</guid>
      <description>This example fetches values at given pixel coordinates in a raster. This example assumes a preloaded three-dimensional raster. For the loading part, see read from a netCDF file or read from a GeoTIFF file code examples.&#xA;Some file formats store values as integers for compactness reasons, but provide a transfer function for converting those integers to &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo; values. Apache SIS can provide either the original integers or the converted values, at user&amp;rsquo;s choice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get the EPSG code or URN of an existing CRS</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/lookup_crs_urn.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/lookup_crs_urn.html</guid>
      <description>The identifier of a Coordinate Reference System (CRS) object can be obtained by the getIdentifiers() method, which usually return a collection of zero or one element. If the CRS has been created from a Well Known Text (WKT) parsing and the WKT ends with an AUTHORITY[&amp;quot;EPSG&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;xxxx&amp;quot;] (WKT version 1) or ID[&amp;quot;EPSG&amp;quot;, xxxx] (WKT version 2) element, then the identifier (an EPSG numerical code in this example) is the xxxx value in that element.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Handle rasters bigger than memory</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/rasters_bigger_than_memory.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/rasters_bigger_than_memory.html</guid>
      <description>This example opens a big GeoTIFF file without reading the tiles immediately. Instead, tiles will be read only when requested by a call to the Java2D RenderedImage.getTile(int, int) method. Loaded tiles are cached by soft references, i.e. they may be discarted and reloaded when needed again. This approach allows processing of raster data larger than memory, provided that the application does not request all tiles at once. It integrates well with operations provided by Apache SIS such as raster resampling and getting values at geographic coordinates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instantiate a UTM projection</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/instantiate_utm_projection.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/instantiate_utm_projection.html</guid>
      <description>The Universal Transverse Mercator (UTM) projection divides the world in 60 zones. If the UTM zone is unknown, an easy way to instantiate the projection is to invoke the universal(…) method on one of the CommonCRS predefined constants. That method receives in argument a geographic coordinate in (latitude, longitude) order and computes the UTM zone from it. It takes in account the special cases of Norway and Svalbard.&#xA;An alternative, more standard, way using geographic coordinates is to format an &amp;ldquo;AUTO&amp;rdquo; authority code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parallel computation</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/parallel_computation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/parallel_computation.html</guid>
      <description>Some grid coverages will read or compute chunks of data only when first requested. For example when a coverage is the result of a reprojection, or when a big coverage uses deferred tile reading. However if tiles are always requested in the same thread, it will result in a sequential, mono-threaded computation. Furthermore it may cause a lot of seek or &amp;ldquo;HTTP range&amp;rdquo; operations if tiles are read in random order.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parse and format MGRS codes</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/parse_and_format_mgrs_codes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/parse_and_format_mgrs_codes.html</guid>
      <description>The following example converts geographic coordinates to Military Grid Reference System (MGRS) codes and conversely. MGRS codes can be seen as a kind of GeoHash but with better properties. Apache SIS supports also GeoHash if desired, in a way similar to this example.&#xA;Direct dependencies Maven coordinates Module info Remarks org.apache.sis.storage:sis-referencing org.apache.sis.referencing Code example Note that all geographic coordinates below express latitude before longitude.&#xA;import org.apache.sis.geometry.DirectPosition2D; import org.apache.sis.referencing.CommonCRS; import org.apache.sis.referencing.gazetteer.MilitaryGridReferenceSystem; import org.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Read raster from a GeoTIFF file</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/read_geotiff.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/read_geotiff.html</guid>
      <description>This example reads data in GeoTIFF format. Contrarily to other formats such as PNG or JPEG, a GeoTIFF file can contain an arbitrary number of images. For this reason, GeoTiffStore does not implement directly GridCoverageResource. Instead, GeoTiffStore implements the Aggregate interface.&#xA;This example assumes that the raster, optionally clipped to a subregion, can fit in memory. For potentially much bigger rasters, see rasters bigger than memory code example.&#xA;Direct dependencies Maven coordinates Module info Remarks org.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Read raster from a netCDF file</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/read_netcdf.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/read_netcdf.html</guid>
      <description>This example reads data in netCDF format. Contrarily to other formats such as PNG or JPEG, a netCDF file can contain an arbitrary number of variables with none of them identified as the main data. Furthermore those data are not necessarily rasters. For this reason, NetcdfStore does not implement directly GridCoverageResource. Instead, NetcdfStore implements the Aggregate interface and the desired variable must be specified. The variables may be instances of GridCoverageResource, but not necessarily.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resample a raster</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/resample_raster.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/resample_raster.html</guid>
      <description>This example reprojects a raster to a different Coordinate Reference System (CRS). This example assumes a preloaded two-dimensional raster. For the loading part, see read from a netCDF file or read from a GeoTIFF file code examples.&#xA;Direct dependencies Maven coordinates Module info Remarks org.apache.sis.code:sis-feature org.apache.sis.feature org.apache.sis.non-free:sis-embedded-data org.apache.sis.referencing.database Non-Apache license. The EPSG dependency is necessary for this example because a Coordinate Reference System (CRS) is instantiated from its EPSG code. But it would also be possible to specify a CRS without EPSG code, for example using Well Known Text (WKT) format.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transform coordinates</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/transform_coordinates.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/transform_coordinates.html</guid>
      <description>The following Java code projects geographic coordinates from the World Geodetic System 1984 (WGS84) to WGS 84 / UTM zone 33N. In order to make the example a little bit simpler, this code uses predefined constants given by the CommonCRS convenience class. But more advanced applications may use EPSG codes or definitions in Well-Known Text (WKT) instead.&#xA;Note: if the result of a coordinate transformation seems wrong, see the FAQ page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transform envelopes (bounding boxes)</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/transform_envelopes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/transform_envelopes.html</guid>
      <description>The transformation of envelopes (or bounding boxes) is a much more difficult task than transforming the four corners of a rectangle. The rectangle straight lines in source CRS may become curves in the target CRS with minimum and maximum values that are not located in any corner. The calculation is also more complicated if the envelope contains a pole or crosses the anti-meridian. Apache SIS handles those complexities in convenience static methods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Union or intersection of envelopes in different CRS</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/envelopes_in_different_crs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/envelopes_in_different_crs.html</guid>
      <description>Before to compute the union or intersection of two or more envelopes (bounding boxes), all envelopes must be transformed to the same Coordinate Reference System (CRS). But the choice of a common CRS is not easy. We must verify that all envelopes are inside the domain of validity of the common CRS, which may require to choose a common CRS different than the CRS of all envelopes. Apache SIS can handle this task automatically.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write a raster to a file</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/write_raster.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/write_raster.html</guid>
      <description>This example saves a raster in PNG format together with its WorldFile PRJ and PGW auxiliary files. This example assumes a preloaded raster. For the loading part, see read from a netCDF file or read from a GeoTIFF file code examples.&#xA;Direct dependencies Maven coordinates Module info Remarks org.apache.sis.storage:sis-storage org.apache.sis.storage Code example The file name in following code need to be updated for yours data.&#xA;import java.io.File; import org.apache.sis.storage.DataStore; import org.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
