<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How to on Apache SIS</title>
    <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in How to on Apache SIS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://sis.apache.org/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Get raster values at geographic coordinates</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/raster_values_at_geographic_coordinates.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/raster_values_at_geographic_coordinates.html</guid>
      <description>This example reads a netCDF file and fetches values at given coordinates. The coordinates can be expressed in different Coordinate Reference System (CRS). Conversions from geographic coordinates to pixel coordinates, followed by conversions from raster data to units of measurement, are done automatically. Raster rata and spatiotemporal coordinates can have more than two dimensions.
This example uses data in netCDF format. A netCDF file can contain an arbitrary amount of variables.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Handle rasters bigger than memory</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/rasters_bigger_than_memory.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/rasters_bigger_than_memory.html</guid>
      <description>This example opens a big GeoTIFF file without reading the tiles immediately. Instead, tiles will be read only when requested by a call to the Java2D RenderedImage.getTile(int, int) method. Loaded tiles are cached by soft references, i.e. they may be discarted and reloaded when needed again. This approach allows processing of raster data larger than memory, provided that the application does not request all tiles at once. It integrates well with operations provided by Apache SIS such as raster resampling and getting values at geographic coordinates.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Resample a raster and write to a file</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/howto/resample_and_save_raster.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/howto/resample_and_save_raster.html</guid>
      <description>This example reads a raster in a GeoTIFF file and reprojects it to a different Coordinate Reference System (CRS). The result is saved as a World File in PNG format.
Direct dependencies    Maven coordinates Module info Remarks     org.apache.sis.storage:sis-geotiff org.apache.sis.storage.geotiff    org.apache.sis.non-free:sis-embedded-data org.apache.sis.referencing.database Non-Apache license.    The EPSG dependency is necessary for this example because a Coordinate Reference System (CRS) is instantiated from its EPSG code.</description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
