<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Release notes on Apache SIS</title>
    <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Release notes on Apache SIS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SIS 0.1-incubating Release notes</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.1.html</guid>
      <description>Release date: 2010-11-10 Next release Previous release Incompatible changes Noticeable changes  This is the first release of Apache SIS (incubator).
Incompatible changes  Not applicable.
Noticeable changes  New Features   [SIS-1] — Import LocalLucene code into SIS [SIS-5] — Website logo [SIS-6] — Create DOAP file for projects.a.o [SIS-7] — Top level pom for SIS [SIS-12] — Write basic SIS documentation for CLI and for WS layer [SIS-15] — Bake in Demo JSP page for initial release  Improvements   [SIS-2] — Stand up SIS website [SIS-3] — Refactor SIS [SIS-14] — Use LatLon class instead of plain double points in QuadTreeData interface [SIS-23] — Brand demo.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SIS 0.2-incubating Release notes</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.2.html</guid>
      <description>Release date: 2012-07-23 Next release Previous release Incompatible changes Noticeable changes  Release from incubator.
Incompatible changes  Not determined.
Noticeable changes  New Features   [SIS-30] — Jetty Integration  Improvements   [SIS-35] — Include JDOM license in the NOTICE file and remove servlet dependency  Bug fixes   [SIS-25] — Location servlet doesn&amp;rsquo;t return correct coordinates for point-radius query region [SIS-26] — Use of Java 1.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SIS 0.3 Release notes</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.3.html</guid>
      <description>Release date: 2013-08-17 Next release Previous release Incompatible changes Noticeable changes  This is the first Apache SIS release as a graduated project (outside incubator).
Incompatible changes  Not determined.
Noticeable changes  New Features   [SIS-62] — Create a sis-utility module [SIS-52] — Create a sis-metadata module [SIS-55] — Skeleton implementation of GeoAPI Citation [SIS-46] — Add sis-console module to current SIS project [SIS-66] — Create new Range class to avoid licensing issues [SIS-77] — Provide an IDE build for Eclipse  Improvements   [SIS-57] — A Logo for SIS [SIS-31] — Website needs a facelift [SIS-38] — Add the missing documentation comments for SIS-core storage [SIS-40] — Add the missing documentation comments for SIS WS layer [SIS-41] — Improve the demo.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SIS 0.4 Release notes</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.4.html</guid>
      <description>Release date: 2014-04-07 Next release Previous release Incompatible changes Noticeable changes  Incompatible changes  Not determined.
Noticeable changes  New Features   Partial implementation of ISO 19111 — Referencing by coordinates. Partial implementation of ISO 19162 — Well Known Text 2.  Improvements   [SIS-68] — Remove LatLon class and replace with DirectPosition [SIS-69] — Remove LatLonRect and replace with Envelope class [SIS-88] — Reduce size of public API [SIS-115] — Ability to set NilReason on Boolean, Integer, Double and String objects [SIS-119] — Support gmx:FileName and gmx:MimeFileType elements [SIS-121] — AngleFormat should be able to optionally omit zero fields [SIS-143] — DefaultGeographicBoundingBox should support spanning of anti-meridian [SIS-158] — Complete JAXB annotations for datum objects  Bug fixes   [SIS-112] — Maven site on Jenkins has broken links [SIS-122] — DefaultRepresentativeFraction needs to implement IdentifiedObject [SIS-132] — Better support for eclipse IDE [SIS-133] — ResourceCompilerMojo should execute only when properties files are modified [SIS-134] — ClassCastException in org.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SIS 0.5 Release notes</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.5.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.5.html</guid>
      <description>Release date: 2015-02-12 Next release Previous release Incompatible changes Noticeable changes  The initial plan for Apache SIS 0.5 was to complete the implementation of Referencing by coordinates (ISO 19111), which started in SIS 0.4. However this work is not yet finished and is re-targeted for SIS 0.6 release. Nevertheless this SIS 0.5 release contains an upgrade of spatial metadata (ISO 19115-1) from the standard published in 2003 to the revision published in 2014 (SIS-94).</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SIS 0.6 Release notes</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.6.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.6.html</guid>
      <description>Release date: 2015-09-16 Next release Previous release Incompatible changes Noticeable changes  The main new features of Apache SIS 0.6 are:
 Support of Well Known Text version 1 and 2 (ISO 19162) for Coordinate Reference System objects. Support of Geographic Markup Language (GML) version 3.2 (ISO 19136) for Coordinate Reference System objects, except DerivedCRS, ConcatenatedOperation and PassThroughOperation. Support of Mercator, Transverse Mercator, Lambert Conic Conformal and Polar stereographic map projections.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SIS 0.7 Release notes</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.7.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.7.html</guid>
      <description>Release date: 2016-05-27 Next release Previous release Incompatible changes Noticeable changes  The main new features of Apache SIS 0.7 are:
 Creation of Coordinate Reference System (CRS) objects from an EPSG code. The list of EPSG codes supported by latest SIS release can be viewed here. Find coordinate operation paths from a pair of CRS, using the EPSG geodetic dataset if possible. Completion of Geographic Markup Language (GML) version 3.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SIS 0.8 Release notes</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.8.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/0.8.html</guid>
      <description>Release date: 2017-11-24 Next release Previous release Incompatible changes Noticeable changes  An important change in Apache SIS 0.8 is the replacement of the deprecated JSR-275 dependency by JSR-363 — Units of Measurement API (this implies an upgrade from GeoAPI 3.0.0 to GeoAPI 3.0.1). Users are encouraged to upgrade to Apache SIS 0.8 or later for resolving this dependency issue.
Incompatible changes  Not determined.
Noticeable changes  New Features   [SIS-128] — Implement the JSR-363 javax.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SIS 1.0 Release notes</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/1.0.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/1.0.html</guid>
      <description>Release date: 2019-09-27 Next release Previous release Incompatible changes Noticeable changes  Apache SIS 1.0 can marshal and unmarshal metadata in XML documents using the new ISO 19115-3 standard. The previous ISO 19139 standard is still supported and automatically recognized at unmarshalling time. This release also contains improvements in reading netCDF files and a beginning of raster support.
Incompatible changes  The following changes in Apache SIS 1.0 are incompatible with SIS 0.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SIS 1.1 Release notes</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/1.1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/1.1.html</guid>
      <description>Release date: 2021-10-06 Next release Previous release Incompatible changes Noticeable changes  Apache SIS 1.1 can read GeoTIFF images, apply raster reprojections and create isolines from rasters. It can read features from a SQL database with the FeatureType inferred by analyzing the database schema. Features can be filtered by the filter API added in this release, including with geometric operations defined by SQLMM.
Incompatible changes  In the sis-utility module, the following classes moved to the org.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SIS 1.2 Release notes</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/1.2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/1.2.html</guid>
      <description>Release date: 2022-05-18 Next release Previous release Incompatible changes Noticeable changes  Apache SIS 1.2 can read World Files and ESRI ASCII grid and BIL/BIP/BSQ rasters, in addition to GeoTIFF support added in SIS 1.1, and in addition to netCDF support added in previous releases. This release also contains various bug fixes improving the stability.
Incompatible changes  None.
Noticeable changes  New Features   [SIS-529] — Provide native GeoTIFF metadata [SIS-541] — Add &amp;ldquo;World File&amp;rdquo; reader and writer [SIS-540] — Add an ESRI ASCII Grid reader and writer [SIS-543] — Add a BIL/BIP/BSQ data store [SIS-524] — Image masking based on a geometry [SIS-528] — Add a &amp;ldquo;system monitor&amp;rdquo; with visual indication of seek operations [SIS-533] — Add &amp;ldquo;Rotated Latitude/Longitude&amp;rdquo; coordinate operation [SIS-228] — Lambert Azimuthal Equal Area (EPSG:9820) [SIS-229] — Lambert Azimuthal Equal Area (Spherical) (EPSG:1027) [SIS-542] — Mercator auxiliary sphere [SIS-538] — Support ESRI WKT element GEOGTRAN [SIS-539] — Create a &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; group of modules, starting with AWS S3  Improvements   [SIS-300] — Complete the information provided in Citations constants [SIS-520] — SQLStore should avoid creating features with cyclic associations [SIS-514] — GridGeometry.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SIS 1.3 Release notes</title>
      <link>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/1.3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sis.apache.org/release-notes/1.3.html</guid>
      <description>Release date: 2022-12-23 Next release Previous release Incompatible changes Noticeable changes  This release contains an upgrade of the org.apache.sis.metadata.iso.quality package to the ISO 19157:2013 international standard. This release contains also various bug fixes improving the stability.
Incompatible changes  The following changes in Apache SIS 1.3 are incompatibles with the previous release (SIS 1.2):
 In the org.apache.sis.coverage.grid package, the GridEvaluator class has been replaced by the GridCoverage.Evaluator interface.</description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
